- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
Your turn.
轮到你了。
- Uhmmmm...uhnn.
- 嗯……嗯。
Now you.
现在轮到你。
- Hey, Patrick.
- 嘿，帕特里克。
- [sighs]
Yeah, SpongeBob?
- [叹气]
是啊，海绵宝宝？
Do you think maybe it would make
the game more exciting
你认为也许这会让
游戏更精彩
if we played it with...
two sticks?
如果我们玩...
两根棍子？
- Two sticks?
- 两根棍子？
That's against the rules.
这是违反规则的。
You can't change the rules,
SpongeBob,
你无法改变规则
海绵宝宝，
just because I'm winning.
只是因为我赢了。
- I'm sorry, Patrick.
- 对不起，帕特里克。
I'm just so bored playing stick
and a cup.
我只是无聊地玩棍子
和一个杯子。
- Are you tired of playing with
the old stick and a cup?
- 你玩腻了吗
旧棍子和杯子？
both: Yeah.
两人：是的。
- Well, say good-bye to boring,
and hello to Whirly Brains,
- 好吧，告别无聊，
向旋转大脑问好，
the exciting new toy that puts
you in the driver's seat
令人兴奋的新玩具
你坐在驾驶座上
of your own mind!
你自己的想法！
It's so simple.
Just flip your lid,
就是这么简单。
只要掀开盖子，
attach the propeller,
安装螺旋桨，
and watch your brain soar
hundreds of feet into the air
看着你的大脑翱翔
数百英尺高空
as you control the action.
当你控制动作时。
- [mumbling]
- [咕哝]
- [gasping]
- [喘气]
both: Ahhhh.
两人：啊啊啊。
- Get your Whirly Brain today,
and free your mind!
- 今天就获得你的旋转大脑，
并释放你的思想！
- Free my mind!
Free my mind!
- 释放我的思想！
解放我的心灵！
Free my mind!
- [chomping]
- [咀嚼]
both: I want it. I want it.
I want it. No, I want it.
两人：我想要。我要它。
我要它。不，我想要它。
No, it's mine. I want it.
I want it. I want it.
不，这是我的。我要它。
我要它。我要它。
- Sorry to hear about your TV,
SpongeBob.
- 很遗憾听到你的电视的事，
海绵宝宝。
- Whirly Brains are available
now at Bikini Bottom Toy Shop.
- 旋转大脑可用
现在在比基尼泳裤玩具店。
both: Whirly Brains! Whirly
Brains!
两人：旋转的大脑！旋风
脑子！
Whirly Brains! Whirly Brains!
Whirly Brains!
旋转的大脑！旋转的大脑！
旋转的大脑！
- Okay, Patrick, just let me
flip your lid,
- 好吧，帕特里克，让我来吧
掀开你的盖子，
so I can attach the propeller
directly to your brain.
这样我就可以装上螺旋桨
直接到你的大脑。
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- Buh-ha-ha.
- 哈哈哈。
- Step one...[mutters]...oh, I
see what to do.
- 第一步...[嘀咕]...哦，我
看看该怎么做。
Ahhh!
啊啊！
- Ahhh!
- 啊啊！
- It's just me, Patrick.
- 只有我，帕特里克。
- Ohhh.
- 哦哦。
[exhales]
[呼气]
- Now you do me.
- 现在你做我了。
- Boo!
- Ahhh!
- 嘘！
- 啊啊！
It's time to free our minds.
是时候解放我们的思想了。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Whoa, Patrick.
哇，帕特里克。
I've never seen the world from
this angle before.
我从未见过这个世界
之前这个角度。
- And the propeller tickles my
think folds.
- 螺旋桨让我发痒
认为折叠。
[laughs]
[笑]
Hey. Hey.
Hey, SpongeBob, eye bump.
嘿。嘿。
嘿，海绵宝宝，眼睛肿了。
- Eye bump.
- 眼睛肿块。
Ow!
噢！
Patrick, no more eye bumps,
okay?
帕特里克，不再有眼肿，
好吗？
- I feel you.
- 我感觉到你了。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
[laughter]
[笑声]
both: Brain freeze!
两人：大脑冻结！
*
- Meow.
- 喵。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Hey, Patrick.
- 嘿，帕特里克。
* I know who we can spy on
*我知道我们可以监视谁
- Ahh, the sanctity of my
bathroom,
- 啊，我的神圣
浴室,
the only place in the world
where I can
世界上唯一的地方
我可以在哪里
let it all hang out.
让一切都结束吧。
Ahh, me.
啊，我。
- Hey, where's Squidward?
- 嘿，章鱼哥在哪儿？
I'm sure I saw him in here.
我确信我在这里见过他。
- Well, maybe he fell in the
toilet?
- 好吧，也许他掉进了
厕所？
I'll check.
我会检查一下。
Squidward,
are you in here?
章鱼哥，
你在这儿吗？
Did you fall in?
你掉进去了吗？
Squidward!
章鱼哥！
- Stop serenading me, you sap.
- 别再给我唱小夜曲了，你这个笨蛋。
It's my day off.
Now, go away.
今天是我休息日。
现在，走开。
- Ahh!
- 啊！
- Found him.
- 找到他了。
- Yup, that's him.
- 是的，就是他。
Hi, Squidward.
嗨，章鱼哥。
- Aliens from Mars!
It's an invasion!
- 来自火星的外星人！
这是入侵！
Waaahhhh!
哇啊啊！
Ugh!
啊!
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[shouting]
[喊叫]
both: Whoo-hoo-hoo!
两人：呼呼呼！
Whoooa!
哇哦！
Whoo-whoo!
呼呼！
Whirly Brains are go!
旋转大脑出发了！
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
[both slurping]
[两人都发出咕噜声]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- She spit in his face.
[laughs]
- 她吐口水在他脸上。
[笑]
[both munching]
[两人都在咀嚼]
- Mrs. Puff, we've been dating
for 16 years now,
- 帕芙女士，我们一直在约会
16年来，
so I was sincerely hoping that
today
所以我真诚地希望
今天
might finally be the day that...
也许终于有一天……
- Yes, Eugene?
- 是的，尤金？
- That I steal a little kiss?
- 我偷了一个小吻？
- Oh.
- 哦。
Oh, Eugene, I thought you'd
never ask.
哦，尤金，我以为你会
永远不要问。
- C'mere you.
- 来吧，你。
[both farting]
[都放屁]
- Ohh.
- 哦。
- What a woman.
- 真是个女人啊。
- Oh, Eugene.
- 哦，尤金。
[laughter]
[笑声]
[both farting]
[都放屁]
[laughter]
[笑声]
both: Ow.
What was that?
两人：噢。
那是什么？
- Ooh, that smarts.
- 哦，这很聪明。
[laughs]
Bull's-eye.
[笑]
靶心。
- I thought we were the first
kids on the block
- 我以为我们是第一个
街区里的孩子们
to get Whirly Brains.
获得旋转大脑。
- What are you, thick?
- 你是什么，厚？
Every kid in
town's got a Whirly Brain.
每个孩子在
镇上有一个旋转大脑。
Pssh!
嘘！
- Daddy, Daddy, can I have a
Whirly Brain too?
- 爸爸，爸爸，我可以要一个吗？
还有旋脑？
- Absolutely not, son.
- 绝对不是，儿子。
Your brain is your body's most
important organ, not a toy.
你的大脑是你身体最重要的部分
重要的器官，不是玩具。
- [sobbing]
- [抽泣]
- Pow!
- [laughs]
- 战俘！
- [笑]
- Hooray!
- 万岁！
Now we can play Whirly Brains
with the whole neighborhood.
现在我们可以玩旋转大脑了
与整个社区。
Hey, kid, race you the end of
the street.
嘿，孩子，和你赛跑到底
街道。
- Eat my brain stem, slowpoke.
- 吃掉我的脑干吧，慢吞吞的。
[all farting]
[全放屁]
- Get ready, get set, punch it.
- 准备好，准备好，出拳。
[tires squealing]
[轮胎吱吱声]
[farting]
[放屁]
[both coughing]
[两人都咳嗽]
- Heh-heh-heh-heh-heh-heh.
- 嘿嘿嘿嘿嘿嘿嘿。
- Ahh! Ohh! Huh?
- 啊！哦！啊？
- Yes!
We're gonna beat him, Patrick.
- 是的！
我们要打败他，帕特里克。
We're gonna win!
我们会赢！
- Fly your toys into my yard,
will you?
- 把你的玩具飞到我的院子里，
你会吗？
Well, they're mine now.
好吧，他们现在是我的了。
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
- Hey, what's going on?
Everything went dark.
- 嘿，怎么了？
一切都变暗了。
Patrick, can you see
anything?
帕特里克，你能看到吗
有什么吗？
- Only the dismal abyss of black
nothingness.
- 只有黑色的惨淡深渊
虚无。
- Oh, our remote controls are
dead too.
- 哦，我们的遥控器是
也死了。
Oh, Patrick, I don't want to
jump to any conclusions here,
哦，帕特里克，我不想
在这里跳到任何结论，
but I think that we have lost
our minds.
但我认为我们已经输了
我们的想法。
- [chuckling]
- [轻笑]
M-O-O-N.
月亮。
That spells moon.
那拼的是月亮。
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
- Okay, don't panic, Patrick.
- 好吧，别惊慌，帕特里克。
We'll find them.
Just take it easy.
我们会找到他们的。
放轻松吧。
Take it easy.
Patrick, take it easy!
别紧张。
帕特里克，放轻松！
- I'm taking it easy, SpongeBob.
- 我很轻松，海绵宝宝。
- Our brains are probably right
around here somewhere.
- 我们的大脑可能是对的
就在这附近的某个地方。
Here, brains.
Brains.
在这里，大脑。
大脑。
Here, boy.
在这里，男孩。
- Here, brains.
- 在这里，大脑。
- Brainy, where are you?
- 聪明，你在哪里？
- Brain, brain, brain.
- 大脑，大脑，大脑。
I think I found it, SpongeBob.
我想我找到了，海绵宝宝。
- I found mine too.
- 我也找到了我的。
Aw, darn it.
I still can't see.
噢，该死。
我还是看不清。
- Yeah, and my brain won't fit
back in.
- 是的，我的大脑不适应
回来。
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
- Oh, uh, ma'am,
you forgot something.
- 哦，呃，女士，
你忘记了什么。
- That's okay.
You can keep it.
- 没关系。
你可以保留它。
- I'll take it.
- 我要买它。
Oh, yeah, looking good.
哦，是的，看起来不错。
- Ew.
Gimme that.
- 呃。
给我那个。
- Aw, man, that felt all
squishy.
- 噢，伙计，这就是我的感觉
软软的。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Patrick, we need help.
Let's call Sandy.
- 帕特里克，我们需要帮助。
我们打电话给桑迪吧。
- Okay.
Sandy!
- 好的。
沙！
- Patrick, I meant on the phone.
- 帕特里克，我是说在电话里。
- Hello?
- 你好？
both: Sandy!
两人：桑迪！
- Dang.
- 当当。
You two sure are lucky I
created this
你们两个真的很幸运我
创建了这个
missing brain
detector last summer.
缺少大脑
去年夏天的探测器。
I was beginning to think I'd
never get to use this thing.
我开始以为我会
永远不会使用这个东西。
- I hope we find our brains
soon.
- 我希望我们能找到我们的大脑
很快。
They're probably cold and hungry
by now.
他们可能又冷又饿
到现在为止。
Poor things.
可怜的东西。
- Brain?
- Brain, where are you?
- 脑？
- 大脑，你在哪里？
- Hey, brain.
- Oof!
- 嘿，大脑。
- 噢！
- Come out.
We're looking for you.
- 出来吧
我们正在找你。
- And it looks like you're not
the only critters around these
- 看来你不是
这些周围唯一的生物
parts to lose your minds.
零件失去理智。
Hmm, and my
detector
嗯，还有我的
探测器
is leading us directly
to that house.
直接引导我们
到那所房子。
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- Excuse me, kind sir.
- 对不起，好心的先生。
Would you mind too terribly if
we just came in your house for a
如果你太介意的话
我们刚刚来到你家
minute and looked around for my
friend's missing brains?
分钟，环顾四周寻找我的
朋友脑子没了？
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- We're gonna take that as a
yes.
- 我们会把它当作
是的。
Step lively, fellas.
伙计们，行动起来吧。
[both humming]
[两人都哼哼]
- This place has a ten-gallon
case of the creepies.
- 这个地方有十加仑
令人毛骨悚然的情况。
I wonder what's in...
[gasps]
我想知道里面有什么...
[喘气]
Hey, fellas.
I think I found your brains.
嘿，伙计们。
我想我找到了你的大脑。
both: Hooray!
两人：万岁！
- Hey.
[together] Huh?
- 嘿。
[合]啊？
- What are you sneak thieves
doing in my house?
- 你是什么偷偷摸摸的小偷
在我家做什么？
Them brains violated my air
space, and I'm keeping 'em.
他们的大脑侵犯了我的空气
空间，我保留它们。
I'm calling the cops.
我要报警了
both: Oh, don't send us to jail.
Oh, no, no, no.
两人：哦，别把我们送进监狱。
哦，不，不，不。
Please, no, no.
I don't want to go to jail
拜托，不，不。
我不想进监狱
We were just having fun.
We're sorry.
我们只是玩得很​​开心。
我们很抱歉。
- Sorry nothing.
Look old-timer, one false move,
- 没什么抱歉的。
看看老前辈，一个错误的举动，
and I'll be on you like a
horsefly on a cracker barrel.
我会像一个人一样在你身边
饼干桶上的马蝇。
- Bring it on, slippy whiskers.
- 来吧，滑溜溜的胡须。
I'll twenty-three skiddoo your
bee's knees
我会二十三岁的你
蜜蜂的膝盖
with wooden nickels,
sister.
与木制镍币，
姐姐。
- All right, now, you listen to
me, ya twisted coot.
- 好吧，现在，你听着
我，你这个扭曲的傻瓜。
You can't steal somebody's brain
你无法偷走别人的大脑
just because it flies
into your yard.
只因为它会飞
到你的院子里。
That's "brainnapping,"
and it looks like I'll be
这就是“烧脑”
看来我会
the one calling the police.
那个报警的人。
- Ooh, I love it when Sandy gets
aggressive.
- 哦，我喜欢桑迪出现
具有侵略性。
Let's give her some room.
我们给她一些空间吧。
Yow!
- Oof!
哟！
- 噢！
- Oh.
- 哦。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
- Oh, Brainy, you're back.
- 哦，聪明，你回来了。
[together]
Oh! Hey-hey-hey!
[一起]
哦！嘿嘿嘿！
- Ahh!
- 啊！
Phew, I'll never be a
"no-brainer" again.
唷，我永远不会成为
又是“无脑”。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Everyone has their brains
back,
- 每个人都有自己的大脑
回来，
so I'ma let it go this time,
所以这次我就放手了
but if you steal as much as a
beach ball, so help me, I'll...
但如果你偷了多达
沙滩球，所以帮帮我吧，我会...
- [sobbing] I'm sorry,
squirrel lady,
- [抽泣] 对不起，
松鼠小姐，
I just couldn't take watching
all the kids have fun in the
我实在无法忍受观看
所有的孩子都玩得很开心
air while I'm stuck here with
this
当我被困在这里时空气
这个
crotchety cane on the ground.
地上的拐杖。
both: Awwww.
两人：哇哦。
- Well, I think we've got a cure
for what ails you,
- 好吧，我想我们找到了治疗方法
对于你的不适，
right, SpongeBob?
对吧，海绵宝宝？
- Sandy, are you thinking what
I'm thinking?
- 桑迪，你在想什么吗
我在想？
- I think I'm thinking what
you're thinking.
- 我想我在想什么
你在想。
- Patrick?
- My think is clogged.
- 帕特里克？
- 我的思维被堵塞了。
- Wahhh-hoo-hoo!
- 哇喔喔！
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
哈哈哈哈哈哈哈！
Yee-haw!
呀呀！
- Sure was nice of you two to
donate your Whirly Brains
- 你们两个真是太好了
捐赠你的旋转大脑
to the old-timer.
给老前辈。
You fellas did a good deed
today.
你们做了一件好事
今天。
- Oh, no need to thank us,
Sandy.
- 哦，不用感谢我们，
桑迪。
If we can just make one angry
old man happy,
如果我们能让一个人生气
老人高兴，
that in itself is thanks
enough.
这本身就是感谢
够了。
The dignity of the elderly
was the victor here today.
老年人的尊严
是今天这里的胜利者。
- Ha-ha!
Look out, ladies!
- 哈哈！
小心，女士们！
Take a ride
on the love-copter.
搭车
在爱情直升机上。
- The Martians are coming!
- 火星人来了！
Run for your lives!
为你的生命而奔跑！
You're next!
下一个就是你！